(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
（オープニング）
(Opening Animation)
せーの！
Ready, set...!
ポルカ！ポルカ！ポルカ！
Polka! Polka! Polka!
ポルカ、おりよー！
Polka's here!
みんな、今日は尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2023に
来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming to
Omaru Polka's Birthday Festival 2023!
というわけで、ハッシュタグがこちらになっております。
出てる出てる。よしよし。
And here is the hashtag. It's appearing right there.
Good, good.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
特別なこの日にね、最高のゲストも呼んでおりますので。
あ、さっきちょっと声が聞こえたから...
On this special day, I've invited the best guests.
Ah, I heard their voices a little earlier...
見てるみんなもそれ以外の人も楽しんでいただけるように...
え？それ以外って誰だ？まあいいや。
I hope everyone watching and even others can enjoy...
Wait, who's "others"? Oh well.
ちょっとゲストの人に助けてもらおう。
それでは呼んでみましょう。
I'll get the guests to help me out a bit.
Now, let's call them in.
ゲストの人、どうぞ！
Guests, please come in!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
たすけてー！おめでとう！
Save us! Congratulations!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
おめでとう！わちゃわちゃわちゃ...
Congratulations! *Chatter chatter*
止まってくれたか。よし。
You finally stopped? Good.
ちょっと、ポルカの息も止めて...
Wait, you're taking my breath away...
あ、大丈夫？大丈夫？
Ah, are you okay? Are you okay?
スーハースーハー...
Deep breaths...
よし、これで頑張れるぜ！
Alright, now I can give it my all!
あ、お水もお水も飲んどこうか、じゃあ。
Ah, let's drink some water then.
お水飲む？お水大切だよ、本当に。
Drinking water? Water is really important.
こんな短い間にもう、ミオしゃん... 本気の小声で...
In such a short time, Mio-sha... with a serious whisper...
そ、そうだね。今のどうやるの？
Y-Yeah. How do you do that?
それ何？どういう仕組みなの？
What's that? How does it work?
ミオしゃん、本気の小声の話ね。今日は小粋なトーク？
The thing about Mio-sha's serious whisper.
Is today for witty talk?
まあそれは置いといて。えー特別なゲストの方に
来ていただきました。まずはミオしゃん。
Setting that aside. Today, we have special guests.
First, Mio-sha.
ありがとう、本当に来てくれて。
Thank you so much for coming.
ありがとう、呼んでくれて！お誕生日おめでとう！
Thank you for inviting me! Happy birthday!
で、スバルちゃん！
And Subaru-chan!
はーい！遊びに来ました！よろしくお願いします！
おめでとう、ポルカ！
Hi! I've come to play! Nice to meet you!
Congrats, Polka!
早口だな...
That was fast...
何言ってるか聞き取れなかった。
I couldn't understand what you said.
さて、姫！
Now, Himé!
んなぁー！ありがとう！ポルカ、おめでちゅー！
Nnaa! Thank you! Polka, congrats!
可愛い可愛い。
So cute, so cute.
今日はこんなゲストと一緒に歌って遊んでいきたいと
思います！いぇーい！
Today, I want to sing and play with these guests!
Woo-hoo!
みんなも、見てるみんなも盛り上がってくれるように
ハッシュタグね、これね。
To everyone watching, help us get hyped up
with this hashtag.
呟いてください！お願いします！
Please tweet about it! Thank you!
尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2023！よろしくお願いいたします！
Omaru Polka's Birthday Festival 2023!
We count on you!
早速歌っていこうと思うぜ！
みんなと一緒にいたいからね。えーと...
Let's get right into the singing!
I want to be with everyone. Um...
あ, 姫！姫から行きましょう、まずは。
Ah, Himé! Let's start with Himé.
姫とポルカで歌わせていただきます。
Himé and Polka will be performing a song together.
一番目でいいんな？一番目でいいんな？
Is it okay if I'm first? Is it okay if I'm first?
ミオしゃん、スバルちゃん、また後でね！
Mio-sha, Subaru-chan, see you later!
じゃーねー！
Bye-bye!
また後でね。頑張ってね。
See you later. Good luck.
雑だな...
That's so casual...
姫、大丈夫？今日はしっとり歌える？
Himé, are you okay? Can you sing mellowly today?
頑張るのな！しっとり行くぜ！ルーナ、練習したもんな！
I'll do my best! Let's go mellow! Luna practiced!
いっぱい頑張って覚えたの。任せの。
I worked hard to learn it. Leave it to me.
多分、大丈夫な気がする。よし、じゃあ...
I have a feeling it'll be fine. Alright, then...
メリュー
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Melu
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
夕陽が落ちるより
More than the sunset falling
胸が潰れるので
Because my heart is crushed
耳鳴りのような孤独を隠して
Hiding the loneliness like a ringing in the ears
バスに乗った僕は言う
I, who got on the bus, say
君は灰になってゆく
You are turning into ash
例えばこんな言葉さえ
Even if words like these
失う言葉が僕に言えたら
If I could say words that would be lost
灯籠の咲く星の海に
In the sea of stars where lanterns bloom
心臓を投げたのだ
I threw my heart
もう声も出ないそれは
That thing where I can't even speak anymore
僕じゃどうしようもなかったのだ
There was nothing I could do about it
酷く脆い心地
A terribly fragile feeling
酷く脆いのさ
It's terribly fragile
辛いと思えばだけ
If I just think it's painful
古びたバス停の端
At the edge of an old bus stop
傘を持った僕がいる
There I am with an umbrella
今でさえ此処に浮かぶ
Even now, floating here
夜空の隅に足がつくのに
My feet reach the corner of the night sky
心臓が痛いから死んだふりの
Pretending to be dead because my heart hurts
毎日を見なよ
Look at my everyday life
もういっそ死のうと思えたなら
If I could have just decided to die
僕はこうじゃなかったのだ
I wouldn't have been like this
どうせ死ぬくせに
Even though you're going to die anyway
辛いなんておかしいじゃないか
Isn't it strange to say it's painful?
どうせ死ぬくせに
Even though you're going to die anyway
愛せないんな世界の色に
Into the colors of this unlovable world
僕の唄を混ぜて
Mix my song
もうどうかしたいと思うくせに
Even though I want to do something
僕はどうもしないままで
I remain doing nothing
灯籠の咲く星の海に
In the sea of stars where lanterns bloom
心臓を投げたのだ
I threw my heart
もう声も出ないから死んだふりなんて
Pretending to be dead because I can't speak
どうもなかったのに
Was really nothing at all
僕もきっとそうで良かったのに
I should have been that way too
君がずっと遠く笑ったのだ
But you were laughing far away
Daphne, Ficus, Iris, Maackia, Lythrum, Myrica, Sabia, Flos.
flos
作詞・作曲：R Sound Design
Lyrics & Composition: R Sound Design
拝啓 僕の願いよ未来よ
Dear my wishes, my future
絶え間ない後悔よ
My constant regrets
体感八度五分の夢は
The dream of 38.5 degrees
やがて散ってしまった
Has eventually scattered
Daphne, Ficus, Iris, Maackia, Lythrum, Myrica, Sabia.
Cytisus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lycoris.
拝啓 君の思いは憂いは
Dear your thoughts, your sorrows
巡る感情論は
The recurring emotional theories
半径八十五部の世界に
In a world with a radius of eighty-five parts
僕らは生まれたまま
We are born as we are
澄んだ陽射し浴び溢れた今日
In the clear sunlight overflowing today
溢れた今日に
In the overflowing today
薪を焚べて風に乗せて
Stoking the fire, letting it ride the wind
錆びた空を彩る
Coloring the rusted sky
燻んだ日々を丁寧に飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
The flowers carefully decorating the dull days wither soon
飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
The decorated flowers wither soon
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて
Stupid as I am, I wake from my dream
僕は夢から覚めて 綴った意味も無いな無いな無いな
I wake from my dream, and what I wrote has no meaning at all
君が僕にくれた声も色も
The voice and the colors you gave me
揺るぎない愛情も
And the unwavering love too
二人きりの空に光った星も
The stars that shone in the sky when it was just the two of us
疾うに散ってしまった
Have long since scattered away
凪のせのモノクロの部屋に
In the monochrome room of the calm
季節は色褪せて
The seasons fade away
熱を帯びて 鈍んで擦れた街に零れる
Becoming feverish, it spills into the dull and worn city
擦れた街に零れる
It spills into the worn city
荒んだ日々を丁寧に辿った先に花が咲くはず
At the end of carefully tracing the rough days, flowers should bloom
辿った先に花が咲くはず
At the end of tracing, flowers should bloom
利口な僕は夢を見たまま
Clever as I am, I'm still dreaming
僕は夢を見たまま 揺すった振りで水を注いだ
I'm still dreaming, pretending to shake and pouring water
木漏れ日の中で
In the sunlight filtering through the trees
柔らかく咲いた花は
The flowers that bloomed softly
雲の上で違う星で
Above the clouds, on a different planet
夢の先で揺れてる
They are swaying beyond the dream
燻んだ日々を丁寧に飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
The flowers carefully decorating the dull days wither soon
飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
The decorated flowers wither soon
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて
Stupid as I am, I wake from my dream
僕は夢から覚めて 綴った意味も無いな無いな無いな
I wake from my dream, and what I wrote has no meaning at all
不毛な日々を丁寧に綴った紙に花を描いた
I drew a flower on paper where I carefully recorded barren days
綴った紙に花を描いた
I drew a flower on the recorded paper
不遇な僕ら夢に溢れて
Unfortunate as we are, overflowing with dreams
僕ら夢に溢れて 誓った筈も無かった事にした
We overflow with dreams, and decided the vow never happened
Daphne, Ficus, Iris, Maackia, Lythrum, Myrica, Sabia
Thymus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lychnis
Thymus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lychnis, flos
Daphne, Ficus, Iris, Maackia, Lythrum, Myrica, Sabia
Thymus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lychnis
Thymus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lychnis, flos
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent Majority
作詞 秋元康 作曲 バグベア
Lyrics: Yasushi Akimoto / Composition: Bugbear
人が溢れた交差点を
At the intersection overflowing with people
どこへ行く？(押し流され)
Where are you going? (Being swept away)
似たような服を着て
Wearing similar clothes
似たような表情で
With similar expressions
群れの中に紛れるように
As if blending into the crowd
歩いてる(疑わずに)
You are walking (without a doubt)
誰かと違うことに
About being different from someone else
何をためらうのだろう
Why do you hesitate?
先行く人が振り返り
The person ahead looks back
列を乱すなと
And tells you not to break the line
ルールを説くけど
They preach the rules to you
その目は死んでいる
But their eyes are dead
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by adults
初めからそうあきらめてしまったら
If you give up like that from the start
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming can sometimes lead to loneliness
Dreaming sometimes makes you lonely
誰もいない道を 進むんだ
Go down the road where no one else is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if we're in a crowd
YESでいいのか？
Is "YES" okay?
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent Majority
どこか国の 大統領が言っていた
The president of some country said
放棄して声を上げない者たちは
Those who abandon their voices and don't speak up
賛成していると…
Are agreeing...
選べることが大事なんだ
Being able to choose is important
人に任せるな
Don't leave it to others
行動しなければ
If you don't take action
NOと伝わらない
Your "NO" won't be heard
君は君らしくやりたいことをやるだけさ
Just do what you want to do as yourself
One of themに成り下がるな
Don't lower yourself to being just "one of them"
ここにいる人の数だけ道はある
There are as many paths as there are people here
自分の夢の方に歩けばいい
Just walk towards your own dream
見栄やプライドの鎖に繋がれたような
As if chained by vanity and pride
つまらない大人は置いて行け
Leave the boring adults behind
さあ未来は君たちのためにある
Now, the future is for you
NOと言いなよ！
Say "NO"!
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent Majority
誰かの後 ついて行けば
If you follow someone else
傷つかないけど
You won't get hurt
その群れが総意だと
If that crowd is the consensus
ひとまとめにされる
You'll all be grouped together
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't let the adults control you
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If you give up like that from the start
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming sometimes makes you lonely
誰もいない道を進むんだ
Go down the road where no one else is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if we're in a crowd
YESでいいのか？
Is "YES" okay?
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent Majority
お水… お水飲ませて…
Water... let me drink water...
3曲ね、ちゃんと歌ったからね、しっかりお水飲まないとね。
You sang three songs, right? You need to drink plenty of water.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫。
I'm okay.
元気いっぱい！
Full of energy!
はい、というわけでお聞きいただきましたのは、最初にルーナ姫との「迷宮」。
Yes, so what you just heard was, first, "Meikyuu" with Princess Luna.
そして、えーっと、お嬢との「風呂」。
And, um, "Furo" with Ojo.
スラスラ！
Surasura!
そしてスバル殿の「サイレントマジョリティー」でしたー。
And Subaru-dono's "Silent Majority".
この曲たちは何で選んだの？
Why did you choose these songs?
今日はね、裏テーマが低気圧ということで。
Well, the hidden theme today is low atmospheric pressure.
やはり低気圧はバラード、低気圧はやはりシックで、バラード系かなーっていう。
After all, low pressure means ballads, low pressure means chic and ballad-style.
イメージってことね。
So it's an image.
そういうイメージから選んで、これおしゃれやなー、おしゃれに歌いたいなーっていうのから。
I chose based on that image, thinking "This is stylish," or "I want to sing this stylishly."
サイレントマジョリティーはかっこいいから、スバルちゃんいいなーと思って。
Silent Majority is cool, so I thought it would be great with Subaru-chan.
親戚のおじさん？
Like a relative's uncle?
おばさんにしよう。
Let's go with aunt.
おじさんかおばさん！
Uncle or aunt!
でもスバルちゃんが本当に良かったんだよね。
But Subaru-chan was really good.
違うわ！ おばさんにして、じゃなくて。
No! Not the "make it aunt" part.
でもすごいね、ポルカと歌えて楽しかったよ。
But it was great, it was fun singing with Polka.
楽しかった！ ありがとう。
It was fun! Thank you.
ルーナ初めてバラード歌ったの。
It was Luna's first time singing a ballad.
えー、なんかめっちゃ良かったよ。
Wow, it was really good.
ちょっとドキドキしたのなの。バラードだったから。
I was a bit nervous since it was a ballad.
でも素敵だったよ。
But it was lovely.
めっちゃ嬉しい。コメントとかハッシュタグも引き続きよろしくお願いします。
I'm so happy. Please keep the comments and hashtags coming.
なんか、ちょっと頭痛いかもしれないな、なんか。
Um, I might have a bit of a headache, somehow.
うそ、急にじゃん。急に。
No way, that's so sudden.
いよいよ...
Finally...
いよいよだね。
It's finally time.
待て待て、次は、待って、ちょっと...
Wait, wait. Next is... wait a second...
今日、なんか今日、なんかちょっと天気悪くない？
Today... doesn't the weather seem a bit bad today?
ポルポル...
Pol-Pol...
あ、確かにそうだった。今日低気圧きん。
Ah, you're right. Low pressure is coming today.
え！？
What!?
あ、今日低気圧なんですよ。
Ah, it's low pressure today.
痛い、もしかして。
It hurts, maybe?
あ、ちょっと待って、姫。ポルカさ、一番...
Ah, wait a second, Hime. Polka, you know...
生誕祭だから、いつもはね、ちょっと休んでほしいんだけど、
もうちょっと頑張ってもらって、あの...
Since it's your birthday celebration, usually I'd want you to rest,
but please hang in there a bit more...
ほら、あのホロメンからさ、ビデオレター今日もらってるんでしょ。
Look, you're receiving video letters from Holomen today, right?
おお！
Oh!
ここにいる4人以外からももらっているんだ。
You're receiving them from people other than the four here too.
それはね、楽しみだね。
That's something to look forward to.
誰？誰？誰が来るの？
Who? Who? Who's coming?
見たい、見たい。
I want to see, I want to see.
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a second.
あ、どうしたの？
Ah, what's wrong?
ビデオレターは？
What about the video letters?
どうした？
What's up?
みんな...
Everyone...
低気圧に負けてビデオレターが一個も...
Losing to the low pressure, not even one video letter...
...来てない、そうです！
...has arrived, apparently!
ええー！？
Eeeh!?
なんで！？
Why!?
追い打ちすぎだろ！
That's too much of a blow!
はい、低気圧バラエティ、
Yes, Low Pressure Variety,
低気圧バラエティ 低気圧敗北部
Low Pressure Variety: Low Pressure Defeat Club
低気圧敗北部！
Low Pressure Defeat Club!
はい、みんな集まってるね。
Yes, everyone's gathered.
集まってるね、集まってるね。
Gathered, gathered.
始まる、始まる。
It's starting, it's starting.
・低気圧敗北部 部員・ 尾丸ポルカ
Low Pressure Defeat Club Member: Omaru Polka
始まってるよ、もう。
It's already started.
今日もね、早速始めていく。早速。
We're starting right away today too. Right away.
低気圧の低気圧部の活動だっていうこと。
This is the activity of the Low Pressure Club.
そうだね。あ、あ、なんだかな、なんだかな。
That's right. Ah, ah, somehow, somehow...
・低気圧敗北部 ・ 大空スバル
Low Pressure Defeat Club: Oozora Subaru
低気圧、なるほど。
Low pressure, I see.
やばいよね、活動していきたいんだけど。
It's tough, but I want to do the activities.
・低気圧敗北部 ・ 大神ミオ
Low Pressure Defeat Club: Ookami Mio
なんか、なんか、暑くなってきちゃった。
あ、頭痛いな、なんかちょっと。
Somehow, somehow, it's getting hot.
Ah, my head hurts a bit, somehow.
あ、ちょっと痛いかもしれんな。
Ah, it might hurt a bit.
・低気圧敗北部 ・ 姫森ルーナ
Low Pressure Defeat Club: Himemori Luna
確かに痛いかもしれないな。
It might indeed hurt.
まあ、みんなとりあえず落ち着いてね。
Well, everyone, calm down for now.
我ら低気圧敗北部は、
We, the Low Pressure Defeat Club,
低気圧よわよわの猛者たちが集いし部。
Is a club where champions weak against low pressure gather.
今日も低気圧に、日々ね、負けながら、いつか勝てるその日を、
While losing to low pressure every day, dreaming of the day we win...
その日を夢見て、低気圧の研究を欠かさない。
Dreaming of that day, we never stop our low pressure research.
だがしかし！この中に、
But however! Among us,
一人低気圧に強い人がい...
there seems to be one person who is strong against low pressure...
...るらしいね。
...so I've heard.
いるらしい。うん。
Seems so. Yeah.
はい！というわけでね、はい。じゃあ、今日もまずはね、
Yes! And so, yes. Well, first for today...
低気圧について、学んでいくよ。頑張るよ、今日。
we're going to learn about low pressure. I'll do my best today.
じゃあ早速さ、問題いこう。問題。
Then right away, let's go with a question. A question.
問題するよ。
I'll give a question.
第1問。
Question 1.
低気圧になると体に起きる現象を答えよ。はい。
Answer what phenomenon occurs in the body when atmospheric pressure is low. Yes.
第1問 低気圧になると体に起きる現象は？
Question 1: What phenomenon occurs in the body when atmospheric pressure is low?
現象？あ、早押し、あ、早押し、何でもいいよ。
早打ちでもいいし。早打ち...
Phenomenon? Ah, quick answer, ah, quick answer, anything is fine.
Quick writing is fine too. Quick writing...
...我慢、何でもいいけど。じゃあ、スバル、なんかスバルのフリップここ出すよ。
...endurance, whatever. Well, Subaru, I'll show Subaru's flipboard here.
え、ちょっと待ってよ！まだ書いてないよ！
Wait, wait! I haven't written it yet!
書いて、なんか書いてるけど。てい、低気圧？
Write it, she's writing something. Low pressure?
低気圧？
Low pressure?
スバル... 乙女... 何これ？
Subaru... maiden... what is this?
乙女？違う！低気圧だろ！違う！低気圧だって！ねえ！
Maiden? No! It's low pressure! No! I said low pressure! Hey!
何が違う...
What's different...
やべえのら、低気圧。やべえのら。ルーナ書いてる。
It's bad, low pressure. It's bad. Luna's writing.
やべえのら しゅば
It's bad-nora. Shuba.
要は、あの、低気圧の、低気圧をもろに受けていると。
Basically, well, they're receiving the low pressure, the low pressure directly.
部活だぞ！これでさ、会話するやつじゃないんだ。
This is a club activity! This isn't for having a conversation like this.
要は、あのなんか屈強な何かで、なんか倒すんでしょ、低気圧を。
Basically, you're going to defeat the low pressure with something strong, right?
そう！
Exactly!
そうだよ、みおしゃ。みおしゃ、ちゃんと答え書いてるもん。
That's right, Mio-sha. Mio-sha has written the answer properly.
みおしゃのフリップ。何これ？
Mio-sha's flipboard. What is this?
だるい だるい だるい だるい だるいだろう
Dull, dull, dull, dull, it's dull, isn't it
ねえ、なんか、やばい、だるい。頭痛い。ああ、もういい。
Hey, somehow, it's bad, I'm sluggish. My head hurts. Ah, enough already.
みおしゃ、ぶち切れちゃってるよ。怖すぎる、もう。
Mio-sha is snapping. It's too scary.
要は、低気圧で、だるいだるいだるいだるいってなるんだよ。
Basically, due to low pressure, you get all dull, dull, dull, dull.
じゃあみおしゃステップ、みおしゃステップ。みおしゃステップができない。
Then Mio-sha step, Mio-sha step. I can't do the Mio-sha step.
どうやるのみおしゃステップって. こんな感じ？
How do you do the Mio-sha step? Like this?
なんかちょっと違うな。
Something's a bit off.
違う、ポルポル、こうだよ！
No, Pol-Pol, it's like this!
あ、スバルが近いかな。こうだよ。
Ah, Subaru is close. Like this.
ポルポル、本当にお前低気圧に敗北してるのか？
Pol-Pol, are you really losing to low pressure?
頭痛てえんだよ、やっぱり。
My head hurts after all.
じゃあ、ルーナ姫に模範解答書いてもらおう。
Then, let's have Princess Luna write a model answer.
低気圧になると起きる現象、これは...
The phenomenon that occurs when atmospheric pressure is low, it is...
どうだ？
How is it?
頭痛 眠い だるい >_<
Headache, Sleepy, Sluggish >_<
姫……
Luna-hime...
おんな……おぉ！頭痛、眠い、だるい。
Oh! Headache, sleepy, sluggish.
わかる、わかるなどと。
I get it, I get it.
頭痛、眠い、だるだる、死ぬ……
Headache, sleepy, sluggish... I'm dying...
死ぬ！？もう大変なことになっとるわ。
You're dying!? It's that serious!?
そんなことにまでなられるの？
Can it really go that far?
やばくない？
Isn't that bad?
つらすぎるよね、これ。
It's so painful, right?
ポルポルならわかるよね。
Pol-Pol understands, right?
わかるよ。
I get it.
あの、起き上がれない。
Like, you can't get up.
なんならさっきもポルカ始まるまで、もうそこの……
客席のイスがあるのに……
Actually, right before this started, even though
there are guest seats over there...
低気圧来てる！来てるよ、これ！
Low pressure is coming! It's here!
客席のイスがあるのにこれでドンって寝てたもん。
There are guest seats, but I was just sleeping
there like this.
寝てたね。
You were sleeping, weren't you?
地獄。
It's hell.
そうね。
Yeah.
だるさが来てるね。
The sluggishness is coming.
じゃあ、ミオしゃも普通にさっきの「だるい」がいいの？正解。
Now, Mio-sha, is "sluggish" the right
answer for you too?
あれが正解なの？ミオしゃの。
Is that the correct answer for Mio-sha?
ミオしゃの中の正解はなんかあるの？
Do you have a correct answer in your mind?
え……ちょっと……あ、え……え……
Um... well... uh... uh...
永眠...ってコト？！
Eternal sleep... you mean?!
永眠...ってコト！？
Eternal sleep... you mean!?
さっきの！さっきの！
That's what she said earlier!
ミオしゃ！風に引っ張られて！風に引っ張られて！
Mio-sha! You're getting carried away by the mood!
ミオしゃ！風に引っ張られて！
Mio-sha! You're getting carried away!
さっき「死ぬ」って言ったからね。
Because I said "I'm dying" earlier.
そうそう、そういうこと。
Right, that's right.
唯一ふざけられる、ミオしゃがふざけられる場所が
ここってことなんだよね。
This is the only place where the serious
Mio-sha can fool around.
なるほどね。
I see.
じゃあスバルさんもお手本見せてください、低気圧敗北民として。
Now, Subaru-san, show us your example
as a low-pressure veteran.
おなかがへる!!!
I get hungry!!!
おなかがへる！！！
I GET HUNGRY!!!
ちょっと待て！新しく書き直しただろ、お前！
Wait a minute! You just rewrote that, didn't you!?
その鳥みたいな生物は何よ！
And what's with that bird-like creature!?
やっぱりその「だるいだるい」を引き継いでるの、これは！
You're just using "sluggish" over and over to hide it!
どうしてなーの！
How is it!?
え、ちょっと待って、低気圧の「気」もう一回見ていい？
Wait, let me see the "Ki" (pressure)
of low pressure again.
低気圧の「気」何、これ？
What is this "Ki" in low pressure?
おなべ！おなべ！
HUNGRY! HUNGRY!
暴力が足りねーな、これ！
You're just being violent!
え、なんかやってるよ！
Wait, you're doing something!
まあ合ってるよ。
Well, it's correct.
まあ合ってるよね。
It's correct, isn't it?
あ、ちゃんと描き直したり。ギリ合ってるみたいなとこある。
It's like it's barely correct.
言いがかりはやめてくださいよ！
Stop making up excuses!
おなかがへる！でもそれより気になるのは、
おなかが減りますか？低気圧で。
But more importantly, do you really get hungry
because of low pressure?
おなか減ります！低気圧じゃないときも減ります！
I get hungry! Even when it's not low pressure,
I get hungry!
だって永眠よりは可能性があるでしょう、絶対！
Because it's more possible than eternal sleep, right?
どういうこと！？
What do you mean!?
でもだるいだるいだるいだるい来てますよ、ミオしゃは。
But Mio-sha is just saying "sluggish"
over and over.
だるいだるいだるいだるい……元気すぎるだろう！
Sluggish, sluggish, sluggish... You're too energetic!
なるほどね。
I see.
ということで、はい。まあ皆さんお察しの通りね、
この人は低気圧弱くないっす。
As you can see, this person is not affected by
low pressure at all.
なんだって！？低気圧！かかってこいや！
What!? Come on, low pressure! Bring it on!
ほら！かかってこいや！
Bring it on!
台本通りのセリフ読んで！
You're just reading the script!
台本にねえよ！
It's not in the script!
元気すぎるのよ！
You're too energetic!
台本なしだよ！
I'm not following a script!
そうです。低気圧を感じたことがあまりない。
Yes, she doesn't really feel low pressure.
マジ？
Really?
でもさっきさ「眠いかもしれない、これは低気圧ってこと？」
って言ってたら……
But earlier you said, "I might be sleepy,
is this low pressure?"
言ったら、ミオしゃが「スバルご飯食べたからそれ……」って。
Then Mio-sha said it's because Subaru ate food.
血糖値スパイクだな、それ。
It's just a blood sugar spike.
それだけじゃないか！
It's not just that!
違うみたいですね。
Seems so.
ポルカもでもほぼほぼんなたんが書いてるように、
頭痛？頭痛い。眠気？うん。
Luna also wrote things like headache,
sleepiness...
だるい、うん。
Sluggishness, yeah.
起き上がれない、うん。
Can't wake up, yeah.
やる気ない、うん。
No motivation, yeah.
もう無理、うん。
Already impossible, yeah.
もうなんか、もうなんか何もやりたくないやりたくない。
Already just don't want to do anything.
やる気ないは気のせいなんじゃないの？
Isn't the "no motivation" part just your usual self?
え！これは低気圧！
Hey! It's because of low pressure!
根性そうやってすぐ根性論とかなんのか知らないけどさ！
Don't just blame it on spirit or willpower!
根性論！根性論！
Spirit! Spirit!
ルーナさん見て。今だにプロ意識高いから
フリップでもこんなこと書いてる。
Luna-san, look! Her professional spirit is still high,
look at her flip chart.
すごいいいよ、このプロ意識。
This is amazing professional spirit.
ねむい (・o・)
Sleepy (・o・)
眠いって！
Sleepy!
低気圧に対するプロ意識の高さ競ってんのかよ、ここ！
She's competing for professional spirit
regarding low pressure!
そういうこと。
That's how it is.
眠い、眠いね。なるほどね。
Sleepy, sleepy, sleepy...
ちなみに今日の夜から、んーと明日、明日あたりがピークかな？
By the way, from tonight... or maybe tomorrow is
the peak?
ポルカも来てるんだけど、ミオしゃは明日っぽいね。
Polka is already feeling it, but Mio-sha seems
to be tomorrow.
うちはまだ来てない。
I haven't felt it yet.
何が来てんの？
What's coming?
低気圧。
Low pressure.
天気の子？どういうこと？どういうこと？
Weathering with You? What do you mean?
ね、今から来るよ。気圧が……来るよ！
It's coming... the pressure is coming!
嫌すぎんの、その天気の子！なんて！なんてよ、その天気の子！
I hate that Weathering with You! Why!
色んな意見出てますけれども、まだ欲しいですか？
We've had many opinions, do you want more?
いや、まだ欲しくはないですけど。
No, I don't want more...
ミオしゃがなんかまたね、なんか「だるいだるいだるい」って
LINEスタンプみたいなのを発売しようとしてるから。
Mio-sha is trying to sell "Sluggish" LINE stickers
like this.
何これ、新しいの。何これ？
What's this new one?
低気圧部 寝ちゃったわ
Low Pressure Club - I fell asleep
低気圧部！寝ちゃったわ。
Low Pressure Club! I fell asleep.
ミオしゃ本当に面白すぎるよ、それ。
Mio-sha is too funny!
いろんな、いろんな意見が出ましたが、
Various, various opinions were given, but...
ただまあ、私、部長です。
...well, I am the club leader.
まあまあまあまあ。
Well, well, well, well.
低気圧のことわからない。
I don't actually understand low pressure.
え？え？どういうこと？
Eh? Eh? What do you mean?
低気圧部長なのに？部長なのにわからないんですか？
Even though you're the Low Pressure Club leader?
You don't know despite being the leader?
違う、言い訳に使ってるわけでもないんだけど、わかんないんだよ。
No, I'm not using it as an excuse,
but I just don't know.
わかんない？わかってねえ！
You don't know? She doesn't know!
なぜこんなに頭が痛くて眠いのかがわからない。
I don't know why my head hurts so much
and why I'm so sleepy.
わかんねえくせに都合よく頭が痛かったのか、こいつ！
You didn't even know, and yet you
conveniently had a headache?!
ひどいや！
How mean!
部長としてポルカ情けないよ。
As the leader, Polka feels pathetic.
もうこの部も解体だよ。
This club is already disbanding.
えー！？困ります！
Eh?! No way!
でもそれは困るでしょ。
But that's a problem.
だって今日集まったばっかだしね。
We only just gathered today, after all.
そうなんだよ！集まったばっかなんだよ！
Exactly! We just got together!
本日はなんと、特別ゲストにお越しいただいております！
Today, surprisingly, we have a
special guest with us!
繋がるかな？
Will the connection work?
誰？誰？誰？山岸さーん！
Who? Who? Who? Miss Yamagishi!
山岸です！
It's Yamagishi!
はい、現場の山岸です！
Yes, it's Yamagishi on the scene!
初めまして！本物だ！
Nice to meet you! It's the real deal!
初めまして！よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you! Please treat us well.
気象予報士、ウェザーニュースキャスターの山岸愛梨と申します。
I am Airi Yamagishi, weather forecaster and WeatherNews caster.
気象予報士/ウェザーニュースキャスター 山岸愛梨
Weather Forecaster / WeatherNews Caster - Airi Yamagishi
ポルカさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Polka-san, Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！誕生日だった、忘れてやってもらいましたけど、
Thank you! It was my birthday, I'd forgotten even
though they'd celebrated it...
低気圧で忘れてた。
...I forgot because of the low pressure.
いやね、もうホント凄いんだよ。この山岸さんが来てくれたこと、
I mean, it's really amazing. Ms. Yamagishi
being here...
皆さんどれぐらい凄いかわかるかな？ちゃんと。
...do you guys realize how amazing it is? Honestly.
いや、だって凄い。ガチ本物だもんね。
Well, yeah, it's amazing. She's the real deal.
ポルカのサーカスにまで来てくれるとか。
Coming even to Polka's circus.
やばすぎ。
This is insane.
気象予報士としても星空案内人などしても
Both as a weather forecaster and a starry sky guide...
ウェザーニュースLiVEを中心に超活躍してる天才で、
...she's a genius who is super active mainly
on WeatherNewsLiVE...
めっちゃ美人なゲストさんです。
...and she's a very beautiful guest.
おおー！可愛い！凄い凄い！
Ooh! So cute! Incredible!
どうしたらいいかわかんない。どうしたらいい。
I don't know what to do. What should I do?
ポルポルのテンションが高すぎ。
Pol-pol's energy is too high.
いやちょっとね、褒めちぎられると困っちゃいます。
Well, I'm a bit troubled by all the praise.
じゃあちょっと低気圧になっとくわ。ふー。
I'll just get into "low pressure" mode for a bit. *Exhale*
やめて！ノリいいんだから！
Don't! You're so easy-going!
MCのお前が低気圧になってどうすんだよ！
What are you doing getting into low pressure
when you're the MC?!
意思疎通がわかんないって言って、山岸さん、ね、意思疎通が難しいっていうか。
I said I don't understand communication, Ms. Yamagishi,
like, communication is difficult.
めんどくせえな、こいつ！めんどくさいね、ホントに。
She's so tedious! Really tedious.
そう、低気圧と我らの関係について聞きたいんです、是非。
Yes, I definitely want to hear about the relationship
between low pressure and us.
我々、いや、低気圧の敗北部が、いつか低気圧に勝てるようなことを、
We, well, the Low Pressure Losers Club,
want you to teach us things...
いろいろ教えていただきたいです。
...so we can eventually defeat low pressure.
はい、任せてください。頑張りましょう。
Yes, leave it to me. Let's do our best.
勝てるのかな？勝ちたい。
Can we win? I want to win.
まずそもそも、ポルカがさっき部長辞めようかなって言ってたように、
First of all, like Polka said earlier about
maybe quitting being leader...
低気圧ってどういう状態のことを言うんですか？
...what kind of state is "low pressure"?
確かに。天気予報でよく登場するので皆さんは聞いたことはあると思いますけれども、
True. You probably hear it often in weather forecasts,
so I think everyone has heard of it...
周囲に比べて気圧の低いところを低気圧って言います。
...but an area where the pressure is lower
than its surroundings is called low pressure.
周りとの差によって決まるので、何ヘクトパスカル以下が低気圧みたいなものはないんですよ。
It's determined by the difference, so there's no set value
like "under X hectopascals" for low pressure.
へー！
Whoa!
低気圧がやってくると、気圧が下がりますよね。
When low pressure approaches, the air
pressure drops, right?
で、この気圧の変化によって引き起こされる不調のことを天気痛って言うんですよ。
And the physical discomfort caused by this change
in air pressure is called "tenkitsu" (weather pain).
皆さん、天気痛です。
Everyone, it's weather pain.
低気圧病とかじゃなくて天気痛って言うんですか？
You don't call it "low pressure sickness" or
something, but "weather pain"?
天気痛って言うんですよ。
It's called weather pain.
気圧とか湿度とか気温の変化によって引き起こされることがあって、
It can be triggered by changes in pressure,
humidity, or temperature...
頭が痛くなったりとか、関節が痛くなったりいろいろ症状があります。
...and there are various symptoms like
headaches or joint pain.
本質だ！本質まで！
The essence! Right to the essence!
だから季節の変わり目って体調崩すんですか？
Is that why we feel unwell during seasonal changes?
そうですそうです。季節の変わり目は気温の変化も大きいですし。
Yes, exactly. At the change of seasons,
temperature changes are also significant.
強いなあ、やっぱり。言うよね。
She's strong. People do say that.
線を越えたらもうヤバいのかなとか思ってたけど、
I thought maybe it gets dangerous if it
crosses a certain line...
こういう上がったり下がったりで変わるっていう感じなんですか？
...but is it more like it changes by going
up and down like that?
そうですね。急激な変化で体調に影響が出ることがあるので、急激な変化です。
That's right. Because rapid changes can affect your
condition, it's about the rapid changes.
きっと飛行機に乗って上に上がったりするときの気圧の変化みたいなことですよね。
It's like the change in air pressure when
you're on a plane going up, right?
天気痛の症状が出る方は、そういう気圧の変化もあまり得意じゃない方が多いと思います。
I think many people who get weather pain symptoms are
also not very good with those pressure changes.
エレベーターの上に行くやつとか、耳が痛いー！ってなるよね。
Like when an elevator goes way up and
your ears hurt! *Aah!*
それだ！
That's it!
それも、ちゃんと、ね？
That too, properly, right?
うん。
Yeah.
苦笑いしてるじゃないか、ちょっと！
He's forcing a smile, wait a second!
普通ではないかもしれないけど、気圧の変化が...
It might not be normal, but the change in pressure...
色々と大きく影響してるんですね。そうですね。
...is having a big impact in various ways. That's right.
はい！聞きたいことがあります！
Yes! I have a question!
おっ、スバルさん、どうしました？
Oh, Subaru-san, what is it?
はい！なんでスバルは低気圧効かないんですか！？
Yes! Why am I not affected by low pressure!?
知らねーよ！
How should I know!?
なんでさ、効く人間と効かない人間がいてさ、
Why are there people who are affected and those who aren't?
確かに気になるよね。弱い人がいるの。
That's true, it is curious. There are people who are sensitive.
そう、だから不思議なんだよ。なんか気圧って目に見えないから、
Yeah, so it's a mystery. Since pressure isn't visible,
「本当に痛いの？」みたいになっちゃうんだよ。
I end up thinking, "Does it really hurt?"
痛いんだよ！頭痛いの！
It does hurt! My head hurts!
わかんない、視聴者さんでも「えっ、何言ってんのポルカ？」みたいな人いるじゃん、本当に。
I don't know, even among the viewers there are people who think, "What is Polka talking about?"
もうそっち側の人間だよ、スバルは！
Subaru, you're one of those people!
「本当に痛いの？今？」みたいな。
Like, "Does it really hurt? Right now?"
弱い人の特徴。
Characteristics of sensitive people.
そう、なっちゃう人はなっちゃうんですか？
Right, why do some people get affected like that?
気圧の変化を感じるセンサーのようなものが、
Something like a sensor that feels changes in pressure
耳の奥にある「内耳」と言われているんですけど...
is in the back of the ear, called the "inner ear"...
そうなんですよ。この変化が大きいとこの内耳が影響しまして、
That's right. When this change is large, it affects the inner ear,
自律神経のバランスが崩れてしまうんですよ。
and the balance of the autonomic nervous system is disrupted.
自律神経。それでか。
Autonomic nervous system. So that's why.
影響してしまうので、内耳が敏感な方は結構影響しやすいと思うので、
Because it's affected, those with sensitive inner ears are easily influenced.
もしかしたらスバルさんは内耳が鈍感なのかもしれません。
So maybe Subaru-san's inner ear is just insensitive.
内耳が鈍感。
An insensitive inner ear.
それって普段大声出してることと関係ありますか？
Does that have anything to do with me always talking loudly?
どうでしょうかね。皆さん結構大きな声で喋ってると思うんですけど。
I wonder. I think everyone here talks quite loudly.
確かに。
True.
内耳が強いんだって！やったー！
My inner ear is strong! Yay!
でもさ、耳が悪いわけじゃないから。よく聞こえるの、逆にいろんな声が。
But it's not like my hearing is bad. I can hear all sorts of voices clearly.
内耳は... 耳は悪い方だぞ、たぶんスバル。
Your inner ear... Your hearing is probably on the bad side, Subaru.
結局自律神経ってことですよね。なんかその...
In the end, it's about the autonomic nervous system. Like...
内耳から入って、その影響で自律神経を崩しやすい人と崩しにくい人で差が出てるってことですかね。
It enters through the inner ear, and the difference is whether your autonomic nervous system is easily disrupted or not.
そうなんです。自律神経が乱れてくると体調に影響が出ることがあるので。
Exactly. When the autonomic nervous system is disrupted, it can affect your physical condition.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
乗り物酔いしやすい方はもしかしたらその傾向があるかもしれません。
Those who get motion sickness easily might have that tendency.
えーっ！乗り物酔いめっちゃする！
What! I get motion sickness so easily!
乗り物酔いしません。
I don't get motion sickness.
えっ！ゲームも酔いません。
What! I don't get game sickness either.
ゲームも酔うんだけど！めちゃくちゃ酔う！やばいくらい酔う！
I get game sickness though! Really badly! It's terrible!
椅子ぐるぐる回っても大丈夫っす。
I'm fine even if I spin around in a chair.
えーっ！？でも低気圧弱いっす。
What!? But I'm weak to low pressure.
不思議だなぁ。でもミオしゃは乗り物酔いだから実際するんだよね？
How mysterious. But Mio-sha gets motion sickness, so you do get it, right?
ルーナも。画面酔いもするし。同じだ。
Luna too. I get screen sickness too. We're the same.
ちょっとルーナと一緒っぽいな。
I'm kind of like Luna.
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
スバルさん。これ痛い人とかはどうやったら治せるんですか？
Subaru-san. How can people who suffer from the pain fix it?
優しいな。聞いてくれるんだ、痛くないのに。
So kind. She's asking even though she doesn't feel the pain.
みんなのために。ホロメンを守るために。
It's for everyone. To protect the Hololive members.
対策はいろいろあるんですけど、
There are various countermeasures,
まずは規則正しい生活を心がける。
but first, try to live a regular lifestyle.
やべえ、ここにいる人たぶん全員ヴァンパイアみたいな生活してます。
Uh oh, everyone here probably lives like a vampire.
早寝早起きとか。
Like early to bed, early to rise.
あー...
Ah...
あとは、ちゃんと1日3食ご飯を食べる。
And properly eating three meals a day.
あー、食べてるみんな？
Ah, are you all eating?
食べてる。やばいやばい。食べてないっぺ。
I'm eating. Uh oh. I haven't been eating.
食べてるからな、あ。あ、そういうことか。
I eat, oh. Oh, so that's it.
守れてません！守れてないかも。
I'm not following that! I might not be following it.
日光を浴びたりとかもしないといけないのかしら、やっぱり。
I guess we have to bathe in sunlight too, after all.
日光も浴びたほうがいいですね。
It's better to bathe in sunlight, too.
浴びてる！ちょっと浴びてる。
I am! A little bit.
カーテン閉めっぱだろ。
You always keep the curtains closed.
えっ、でも、出すと、うるさいな！トラブル起きないだろ！
But if I do that, it'll be noisy! It won't cause trouble!
やめろって！ステイステイステイ！
Stop it! Stay, stay, stay!
山口さんの御前で何をしてるんだ、君たちは！ステイステイステイだぞ。
What are you doing in front of Yamaguchi-san! Stay, stay, stay.
なんかポルカは漢方も勧められたんですよ。五苓散とか。
I was also recommended herbal medicine. Like Goryosan.
ああいうの飲んでたら効くんですかね、いつか。
I wonder if those will work if I keep taking them.
そうですね。漢方も結構天気痛の緩和が期待できるって言われてるので。
That's right. Herbal medicines are said to be effective in relieving weather pain.
お医者さんと相談しながら。そうなんだ。
While consulting with a doctor. I see.
あとはうちはホロライブJPですけど、ENやIDもいて、
Also, we're Hololive JP, but there's also EN and ID,
イングリッシュやインドネシアとかも普通に低気圧で「うわー」「うっぷす」ってなるんですか？
Do English and Indonesian members also get all "Ugh" and "Oops" from low pressure?
日本以外で影響があるか。国によってね。
Whether there's an impact outside of Japan. Depending on the country.
あんまりまだ天気痛って解明されてない部分もあったりするので。
There are still parts of weather pain that haven't been fully explained yet.
判明してない。
It's not yet known.
天気痛が起こりやすい地域
Regions Prone to Weather Sickness
他の国でどれくらいみんながこう困っててっていうのは、まだわかっていない部分もあるんですけれども...
We don't fully know yet how much people in other countries are suffering from this, but...
ま、基本的には、こう日本って多分、天気痛引き起こされやすい条件が色々整ってるんですよね。
Generally speaking, Japan probably has many of the conditions that make it easy for weather sickness to occur.
四季がそう、はっきりしてたりとか、台風がやってきたり。
For instance, the distinct four seasons and the typhoons that hit us.
ま、同じように、結構こう四季があって、
So, in places that also have distinct seasons...
気温の変化が大きくてっていうところは、同じように影響が出て困ってる方もいるんじゃないかなと思います。
...and large temperature changes, there might be people suffering from similar effects.
なるほどー。
I see.
もしも超悩んでたら、海外に住めば、もしかしたら...
If it's really troubling you, maybe if you move abroad...
え、そういうこと？と思ったんだよ、ポルカもそれずっと。
Wait, really? Polka has been thinking that the whole time, too.
解決するかもよ。
It might solve the problem.
あとは逆に、ずっと何にもなんか知らなかった人とかが、
On the other hand, someone who never experienced it...
日本に来て長期滞在して...
...might come to Japan for a long stay and...
「あれ？頭が痛い、ずっと頭が痛い」とか、なったりするのかな、っていうのもすごい謎だし。
...start wondering, "Wait, why is my head always hurting?" It's such a mystery.
確かになー。
True.
で、山岸さんはどうなんすか？やっぱ、低気圧って結構来ます？今日とか。
So, how about you, Yamagishi-san? Do you feel the low pressure much? Like today.
私は、もう全く感じないんですよ。
I don't feel it at all.
えー！？山岸さん！
What?! Yamagishi-san!
仲間だ、仲間だ！スバルちゃんと同じ！
You're one of us! You're just like Subaru!
山岸さんも、あれですか？
Yamagishi-san, are you also...
あの、規則正しい、外に結構行かれるタイプですか？
...the type who leads a regular life and goes outdoors a lot?
私はもう超インドアです。全く出かけない。
I'm a total indoor person. I never go out.
あれ？何を気をつけてるんですか？
Huh? Then what are you careful about?
何も気をつけてないですね。
I'm not careful about anything.
寝るのも遅いし、起きるのも遅いし。
I go to bed late and wake up late.
なんででしょうかね？なんだろ、お母さんやお父さんがじゃあすごい元々低気圧に...
Why is that? Maybe your parents were naturally resistant to low pressure...
え、でもマジでやっぱ生まれた時に決まってんのかな？
Wait, but seriously, maybe it's decided at birth?
え、絶対そうじゃん。
It must be.
変わらないのなら、低気圧の影響。
If the effects of low pressure never change.
でも、苦手な人でも、生活習慣を改善することによって...
But even if you're sensitive to it, by improving your lifestyle habits...
マシになる可能性があるってことですよね。
...there's a chance it could get better, right?
対策方法
Countermeasures
そうですね。規則正しい生活を心がけたりとか。
That's right. Like trying to lead a regular life.
あとマッサージもありますよ。
There's also a massage you can do.
マッサージ！？
A massage?!
くるくる耳マッサージっていうのがありまして。耳の血流を良くするために...
It's called the "Round-and-Round Ear Massage." To improve blood flow in the ears...
こう、耳をですね、引っ張りながら...
...you pull your ears like this...
上、下、横に5秒ずつ引っ張るといい。
...and hold for five seconds each at the top, bottom, and sides.
あとは後ろに5回回す。
Then, rotate them backward five times.
おー、なんか聞いてるような...効いてるこれ？
Oh, I think it's working... Is it working?
わからんな。
I can't tell.
あとは折り畳む。
And then fold them.
耳、耳...でも、アタシ耳触られるの気持ちいいタイプだから...
My ears... But I'm the type who likes having my ears touched...
なんか効いてそうな気がする。
...so I feel like it's working.
でも、山岸さんも思いません？仕事のスイッチ入っちゃうと、これやっても関係なくないですか？
But don't you think so, Yamagishi-san? Once you're in work mode, does this even matter?
え、どういうこと？
Wait, what do you mean?
家でやるとようやくこうスイッチが入る...リラックス的に見てできるとか。
Like, doing it at home finally flips the switch... doing it while relaxed.
確かに、今ちょっと違うかもしれないですね。
True, it might be a bit different right now.
朝昼晩やるといいらしいです。
They say it's good to do it in the morning, afternoon, and evening.
そういうことですよ、皆さん。
That's the thing, everyone.
だから、皆さんが今「うーん」って言ってたら、もしかするとポルカのために頑張ってるからかもしれないっすよ。
So if you're all struggling now, it might be because you're working hard for Polka.
リラックスしてるときにやるとより効果的ということですか？
So you're saying it's more effective when you're relaxed?
そうですね。基本的にはもう天気痛に悩まされてる、
Yes. Basically, before you're troubled by weather sickness...
頭が痛いとか、症状が出る前からやっておくといいらしいので。
...like headaches, doing it before symptoms appear is said to be good.
なるほど。出る前にやんなきゃ意味ないの？
I see. So it's pointless unless you do it before?
もう症状出ちゃってるからダメだよ、ポルポル。もうダメなの？
You already have symptoms, so it's no good, Pol-Pol. Is it too late for me?
でも確かに頭痛とか聞く、なんかさ、頭痛はさ、頭痛がする前に飲めとかさ。
But it's true for headaches too, they say to take medicine before the pain starts.
低気圧のそのさ、ツールみたいなの見ながら、
Looking at those low-pressure tracking tools...
「あ、そろそろ来るから先に飲んでおこう」みたいなのがあったりするんですけど。
...you might think, "Oh, it's coming, I'll take it now," and things like that.
やっぱり薬に頼りすぎるのも良くないですからね。
But then again, relying too much on medicine isn't good either.
だから毎日もうやんなきゃ、これ。山岸さんもやってね。
That's why we have to do this every day. You do it too, Yamagishi-san.
私もやります。全然天気痛ないけど。
I'll do it too. Even though I don't get weather sickness at all.
困ってる子もいるんだよ。教えてくれたから味方だろ。
There are people who are suffering! She taught us, so she's our ally.
なんで山岸さんに言うんだよ。
Why are you picking on Yamagishi-san?
山岸さんどうですか？ここまで話してて、この人たちは楽しそうな人たちですか？
What do you think, Yamagishi-san? Having talked this much, do these people seem fun to you?
低気圧には勝てそうですかね？
Do you think we can beat the low pressure?
そうですね。やっぱりこれだけのもうパワフルなみんななので、勝てると思います。
Well, since you're all so powerful, I think you can win.
やったー！勝てるんだ！
Yay! We can win!
じゃあ今日でこの部活は解散だ！
Then, this club is disbanded as of today!
待ってくれ、待ってくれ！今日初めて初日だけど。
Wait, wait! Today was only our first day!
今日からは「低気圧を解剖する部」じゃなくて、
From today, we're not the "Low Pressure Dissection Club"...
「低気圧敗北改善部」にしよ。
...let's be the "Low Pressure Defeat and Improvement Club."
対策室みたいな感じで
Like we're in a countermeasure room.
山岸さんにもたまに来てもらいたいから
I'd like for Yamagishi-san to come by occasionally,
そういうのにして。うんうん。
so we'll make it like that. Yeah, yeah.
え、お邪魔していいんですか？
Wait, is it okay if I visit?
え！いいの！？面白い！
Eh! Is it okay?! That's funny!
テンション！
Look at that energy!
来てくださいよ！
Please come!
え、マジで行きたいです！また！
Eh, I seriously want to come! Again!
やったー！山岸さん！
Yay! Yamagishi-san!
山岸さん、あの、大丈夫ですか？こめかみに拳銃とか当てられてない？
Yamagishi-san, um, are you okay? You don't have a gun to your head?
言わされてないですか？大丈夫ですか？
You're not being forced to say this? Are you okay?
背中にね、脅されて...
Behind your back, being threatened...
大丈夫です、脅されてないですよ！
I'm fine, I'm not being threatened!
いや私、普段からみんなの配信見てるので！
No, I usually watch everyone's streams anyway!
ええー！！すごーい！！
Ehh!! That's amazing!!
すごく嬉しかったんですよ！
I was so happy!
本当に！やったー！ありがとうございます！
Really! Yay! Thank you so much!
いや、ていうか本当にありがとうございました！
Seriously, thank you so much for everything!
頑張って、頑張って、えーっと低気圧を...
We'll work hard, work hard to... low pressure...
破滅？何だっけ？
Destruction? What was it?
壊滅！壊滅！壊滅！
Eradication! Eradication! Eradication!
壊滅してきます！
We're going to eradicate it!
壊滅！！
Eradication!!
また予報とか見にいけるかな！
I wonder if we can go watch the forecast again!
壊滅！ありがとうございます！
Eradication! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！またねー！
Thank you so much! See you later!
壊滅！壊滅！
Eradicate! Eradicate!
可愛いー！
So cute!
あ、今、やめ時が分かんなくて怖かった...
Ah, I was scared just now because I didn't know when to stop...
「可愛い」ってついつい言っちゃったね。
I ended up saying "so cute" without thinking.
可愛いー！バイバイのタイミングね！
So cute! The timing of the bye-bye!
よし、じゃあみんな、これで耳マッサージもできてきたことだし
Alright everyone, now that we've finished the ear massage,
できた？
Did you do it?
できたー！まぁ、できたかな！
I did! Well, I think I did!
できたことだし、うん！
Now that we've done it, yeah!
よっしゃー！明日に向かって！
Alright! Toward tomorrow!
ゴールデンな明日に向かってね！
Toward a golden tomorrow!
ゴールデン？なんかキュンどうしたん？
Golden? What's with that "Kyunn"?
この今日のヒストリーを忘れずに、
Without forgetting today's history,
向かって歌おう！あっちに行くぞ！
let's sing toward it! Let's go over there!
あっちどこよー！？
Where's "over there"!?
ゴールデンな明日！
A golden tomorrow!
あっち！ヒストリーって言ってたのに！
That way! Even though you said history!
あっち！なんか出てきた！あっち！
Over there! Something came out! Over there!
あっち！なんかあっち低気圧ある！低気圧ある！
That way! There's some low pressure over there! Low pressure!
こっち！こっち！こっち！こっち！
This way! This way! This way! This way!
待って置いていかないで！何で置いていくの！何で置いていくのよ！
Wait, don't leave me! Why are you leaving me behind! Why are you leaving me behind!
ザ・ゴールデン・ヒストリー
The Golden History
作詞：只野菜摘/浅利進吾  作曲：浅利進吾
Lyrics: Natsumi Tadano / Shingo Asari  Composition: Shingo Asari
よっしゃー！！やってきました！！
Alright!! Here we go!!
ゴールデン・ヒストリー！！
Golden History!!
最後はこの曲で、みんなで盛り上がりたいぞー！
For the finale, I want to get hyped with everyone with this song!
行っくぞー！！
Let's go!!
ありがとー！！
Thank you!!
それでは、最初ポルカが突っ込みまーす！！
Now then, Polka is charging in first!!
さあ始めようか
Now, shall we begin?
勝負の時がやってきた
The time for battle has come.
汗かいて前向いてやってきた
Sweating and looking forward, we've come this far.
自然に負けず
Not losing to nature,
不自然に負けず
not losing to the unnatural,
打たれさえして夢見た
I dreamed even while being beaten down.
実れば実るほど ヘイヘイヘイ
The more it ripens, hey hey hey,
分け合える稲穂 ヘイヘイホー
the more ears of rice we can share, hey hey ho.
季節が来れば
When the season comes,
黄金の国
in this golden land,
輝く風よ
oh, shining wind.
南はどうだい ウォーウォー
How is the south? Whoa-whoa.
北まで行くかい ウォーウォー
Shall we go to the north? Whoa-whoa.
純情の宣戦だ
It's a declaration of pure-hearted war.
震えた指にさあ触る
Now, touch these trembling fingers.
愛してる
I love you.
さあ盛り上がっていきましょー！
Now, let's get hyped up!
最高に 最強で 最上の 最大で
To the highest, the strongest, the best, the greatest,
最愛の 未来に 会いに行くから
I'm going to meet the most beloved future.
いくぞー！！
Let's go!!
最高の笑顔で 迎えてほしいよ
I want you to welcome me with your best smile.
時を超え 繋げよう ヒストリー
Transcending time, let's connect our history.
素晴らしい ヒストリー
A wonderful history.
さあ楽しもう
Now, let's have fun.
心に虹飾ろうか
Shall we decorate our hearts with rainbows?
海 山 虹飾ろうか
Sea and mountains, shall we decorate them with rainbows?
顔で笑って
Smiling with our faces,
心で泣いた
we cried in our hearts.
嬉し涙の分までに
To the extent of those happy tears,
笑顔の種をまきましょう
let's sow the seeds of smiles.
世界と一緒に踊りましょう
Let's dance together with the world.
日本が贈る ウォーウォー
What Japan presents, whoa-whoa,
ヒトパレード ウォーウォー
is a parade of people, whoa-whoa.
花咲かせよう
Let's make flowers bloom.
私たちもまた ウォーウォー
We too, whoa-whoa,
歌ってゆきたい ウォーウォー
want to keep on singing, whoa-whoa.
何起させても
No matter what happens,
みんなの勇気になれる 歌たちを
these songs that can give courage to everyone.
盛り上がっていこー！！
Let's keep getting hyped!!
最高に 最強で 最上の 最大で
To the highest, the strongest, the best, the greatest,
最愛の 未来に 会いに行くから
I'm going to meet the most beloved future.
いくぞー！！
Let's go!!
最高の笑顔で 迎えてほしいよ
I want you to welcome me with your best smile.
時を超え
Crossing time
繋げよう
Let's connect our
ヒストリー
History
素晴らしい
Wonderful
It's a golden ヒストリー
It's a golden history
ありがとう！
Thank you!
本当に大好きの歌なので
I really love this song, so...
すごく感動してます！
I'm very moved!
元気いっぱいぶちかまします！
I'm going to give it my all!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
最高！
The best!
最強！
The strongest!
It's a golden history
最上！
The finest!
最大！
The greatest!
It's a golden history
最高！
The best!
最強！
The strongest!
It's a golden history
最上！
The finest!
最大！
The greatest!
最高！最強！
The best! The strongest!
WE CAN GO!!
幾つの違いを
No matter how many differences
超えるたびに強くなる
Each time we overcome them, we grow stronger
もう一歩　もう一歩
One more step, one more step
さあ　さあ　先へ進め
Come on, come on, move forward!
最高に　泣けそうな
The most beautiful light
きれいな　光だ
That makes me want to cry
私が　変われば
If I change,
明日も　変わる
Tomorrow will change too
歴史の上を行く　新しい
Let's leave new footprints
足跡残そう
On history
続いてく
Continuing on,
真っさらな　ヒストリー
A brand new history
歩いてこう
Let's walk along,
ヒストリー
History
黄金の国よ　笑え！
Golden country, smile!
はーい！ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! Thank you very much!
お聴きくださいましたのは、みんなでゴールデン...
What you just heard was, 'Everyone's Golden'...
おっとい、いない。あはは。
Wait, they're gone. Haha.
え、は、帰り道が早いな。
Geez, they left so quickly.
えー、『ザ・ゴールデン・ヒストリー』でした！
That was 'The Golden History'!
ポルカもこれ、みんなで前から歌いたかったんだよね。
I've wanted to sing this with everyone for a long time.
後で語らせていただきますが、
I'll talk more about it later, but...
その前に、えー、お前のポルカ
Before that, um, your Polka's
誕生日記念'23のグッズ紹介です！
Birthday Celebration '23 merchandise introduction!
こちらドン！
Here they are!
尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念2023
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2023
というわけでこちら気になる詳細は、えーと、
So, for the details you're curious about...
ちょっと待ってください。どっちだどっちだ？
Wait a moment. Which one is it?
えーと、こっちかな？
Um, this way?
はい、あ、合ってる。よかった。はい、
Yes, ah, I got it. Good. Yes,
というわけでこれですね。えーと、一品目は
So, this is it. Um, the first item is...
B2タペストリー。こちらなんと、
B2 Tapestry. This is actually...
ギドラ先生描き下ろしになっております！
A new illustration by Gidola-sensei!
いいでしょ。これ、あの、朝のポルカなんやけど、
It's nice, right? This is, um, Polka in the morning,
ちょっと、まあ、若干のフィクションが入ってるというか、
But, well, it's a bit of fiction, or...
ポルカがこんな朝料理するか、朝早く起きるか、
Like whether I'd cook or wake up early like this...
ちょっと、まあ、でも、ちょっと格好つけました。
Well, I was posing a little.
目線はきちんとみんなに向いてるよっていうことで、
My eyes are looking straight at everyone,
まあみんなというか、お前というか、そこというか...
Well, everyone, or you, or whoever's there...
に向いてるよっていう感じですね。そして二つ目は、
It's like I'm looking at you. And the second item is...
ステッカー！こちらモト先生の描き下ろしです！
Stickers! These are illustrated by Moto-sensei!
絵柄はなんと4種類！
There are four different designs!
めっちゃ可愛い！あのなんていうの、この、
They're so cute! Um, what do you call it, this,
ちっちゃい子？ちっちゃい子ね、
Little character? This little one,
めっちゃいい、便利なステッカーだと思います。
It's a really great and handy sticker set.
ステッカーって色んなところにも貼るからな。
You can stick stickers anywhere.
よろしくお願いいたします。そして三つ目は、
I hope you like them. And the third item is...
はいドドーン！書いてある内容が
Ta-da! The content written here...
めっちゃ重いんだよねこれ。座員くん証明書。
It's actually pretty heavy stuff. The Zain-kun ID Card.
あのね、すんげえ重いけど、まあ...
Listen, it's super heavy, but well...
軽い気持ちでお一つ買っていかないか、お姉さん。
Why not buy one with a light heart, miss?
はい、めっちゃ重いです。
Yes, it's really heavy.
裏にも、まあ裏は、あのね、ポルカのメッセージが書いておりますので、
On the back, well, there's a message from Polka,
そちらもよく読むこと！です。はい。
So make sure you read it carefully too! Okay.
そして五つ目ですね。
And the fifth item... wait,
あ、飛んだわ！ごめん違う。こっち、はい！
Ah, I skipped one! Sorry, my bad. Here, yes!
しっぽクッション、四つ目、ダーン！
Tail Cushion, the fourth item, ta-da!
70センチ！ついにきたかしっぽクッション。
70cm! The tail cushion is finally here.
しっぽクッションで、あの、欲しいってよく言われてたんだけど、
A lot of people said they wanted a tail cushion,
ようやく作ることができました。これ、ポルカのしっぽのクッションやでっていうことで、
And I was finally able to make one. This is a cushion of my tail.
まあ大きさはまあ70センチでございます。で、あの、
Well, the size is about 70cm. And, um,
なんて言えばいいのかな、ワッペンみたいのがちょっとついてるんだけど、
How should I put it, there's a little patch-like thing on it,
そこがポルカのオーレズなところなんで、
And that's where Polka's 'Orez' is, so...
そちらもお楽しみにしながら触り心地を楽しんで。
Look forward to that and enjoy how it feels.
君たちそれ、でも何に使うん？
But what are you guys going to use it for?
まぁ、えー、まぁ、先々飛ばしましたけど、シチュエーションボイスになっております。
Well, uh... well, I skipped ahead earlier, but it's a situation voice.
ポルカとのなんでもない休日、さっきの朝のポスターとリンクしております。
An ordinary holiday with Polka, it links back to that morning poster from earlier.
そしてそしてそしてそして！こちらのフルセット全部ご購入いただいた方には！
And, and, and, and! To those who purchase the entire full set!
なんと特典1！尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念直筆サイン入りDora先生描き下ろしポストカード！
Feature 1! Omaru Polka Birthday Commemorative hand-signed postcard illustrated by Dora-sensei!
こちら無制限！
This is unlimited!
頼まれたら書けるだけ書いちゃうのが尾丸ポルカ！
Omaru Polka will write as many as I'm asked for!
しかもね、ちょっとね、変わってんね、表情が。スゥー、Dora先生アザス！
And you know, the expression is a bit different. *inhale* Thanks, Dora-sensei!
えー、この絵本当にポルカ好きなんで、ぜひね、まぁよかったら全部買ってくれたらいいんじゃないでしょうか。
Um, Polka really loves this illustration, so please, if you'd like, why not buy the whole set?
まぁ、なんでこんなに推してるかって言うと、さらにさらに特典2！こちら特典ボイス！
Well, the reason I'm pushing this so much is, even more, Feature 2! This bonus voice!
「もっと一緒に休日」「もっと一緒に休日」「もっと一緒に休日」がついておりますゆえ、
"More Holidays Together," "More Holidays Together," "More Holidays Together" is included, so...
先ほどの休日と合わせて、まぁポルカとのね、休日、それは甘いのかな？しょっぱいのかな？
Combined with the previous holiday, well, a holiday with Polka... will it be sweet? Or salty?
いったいこの料理のように、どんな味がするのかわからないねぇ。どんな味がするんだろうねぇ。
Just like this dish, you never know what it'll taste like. I wonder what it tastes like!
ということでになっております！はい！こちらがポルカのグッズ全てになっております！
So there you have it! Yes! These are all of Polka's merchandise!
とりあえず、まぁまとめると、いっぱいグッズ出るよ。フルセットも出るよ。サイン付き出るよ、無制限だよ。いっぱい、いっぱいあるよ。
To summarize, a lot of merch is coming out. Full set too. Signed ones too, unlimited. There's lots and lots.
で、値段などこちら、サイズこちら、いっぱい書いてあるよ。詳細はサイトまで。発売はこれから。ハッシュタグはこちら。もう全部書いておいた。
Prices and sizes are here, it's all written. Check the site for details. Sale starts now. Hashtag is here. I've written it all down.
よろしくお願いします。あ、あと、えっと、えっと、番組の最後にはメンバー限定の配信も一応、あ、初めてやるんだよ、それ。
Please check them out. Oh, and, uh... at the end of the show, there's a member-only stream... oh, it's my first time doing that.
ねぇ、何すればいいんだろう。何すればいいんだろう。決まってるんだけど、ちょっとあるんで、よろしくお願いいたします。
Gee, what should I do? What should I do? It's decided, but there's something planned, so please look forward to it.
そして、それだけではもしかしたら終わらないかなぁ？何かが上がるかなぁ？これはお楽しみにしておいてください。
And, maybe that won't be all? Will something be uploaded? Please look forward to it.
というわけでポルカ、みんながあんだけ元気くれたから、もう低気圧にも負けない体を持った気がする。
So, Polka feels like I've gained a body that won't lose to low pressure because everyone gave me so much energy.
だから最後に届けたい、その曲。そう、そう。これどうしようかな。曲名言ったらなんか終わりな気がするんだけど... いや言おう。
So finally, I want to deliver that song. Yes, yes. What should I do about this? I feel like if I say the song title, it'll be over... but I'll say it.
それでは、あれだけみんなに支えられましたポルカ。今年一年頑張りたいと思います。
Well then, Polka was supported by everyone that much. I'll do my best this year.
それでは、LOSER。
Now, LOSER.
いつもどおりの通り独り こんな日々もはや懲り懲り
Alone on the street as always, I'm sick of these days
もうどこにも行きやしないのに 夢見ておやすみ
Even though I'm not going anywhere, dream and say goodnight
一生泥沼こんな風に ボンクラな夜に飽き飽き
Stuck in a rut forever like this, I'm bored of these idiotic nights
また踊り踊り出す明日に 出会うためにさよなら
Goodbye, so I can meet the tomorrow where I start dancing again
歩き回ってやっと着いた ここはどうだ 楽園か
I walked around and finally arrived. How is it here? Is it paradise?
今となっちゃもうわからない 四半世紀の結果
I don't even know anymore, the result of a quarter-century
青い顔のあいつまた お腹空かしてあばよ
That blue-faced guy is hungry again, so long
アイムアルーザー
I'm a loser
どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう
If anything, even a distant howl is fine, right?
もう一回もう一回行こうぜ 僕らの声を
One more time, one more time, let's go with our voices
アイムアルーザー
I'm a loser
ずっと前から聞こえてた
I've heard it for a long time
いつかポケットに隠した声が
The voice I once hid in my pocket
あーだのこーだの知ったもんか 採石場の向こうの天候
Like I care about this and that, the weather beyond the quarry
ほら窓から覗いて待ってんのからすりゃ散りぬるを
Look, peering through the window and waiting, for them it's scattering away
嫌みかとも昔の日よ 痒い板もしょうがないの
Whether I like it or not, it's the old days. I can't help it even if it's itchy
今勝ち上がるための お勉強ほら加点教
Now, to win, I'm studying. Look, it's the religion of extra points
踊る阿呆に見る阿呆 ほらそれを端から笑う阿呆
The dancing fool and the watching fool. Look, the fool laughing at them from the sidelines
でかい自意識抱え込んじゃもう 摩耗すり減って残るスパイク
Clutching a huge ego, I'm already worn out and thinning, the spikes that remain
いざ行け　変えてもらうなよ　ほら
Go forth, don't let them change you, hey
なんか今　前髪で　前髪で見えねえ
For some reason, my bangs... I can't see past them
笑っちまうね
It makes me laugh
パッと弾き出して　パッと消え去る　こんな輪廻
Pop out, then quickly vanish, such a cycle of reincarnation
愛されたいなら　そう言えよ
If you want to be loved, just say so
思ってるだけじゃ伝わんないね
It won't get across if you just think it
永遠の淑女も　そっぽ向いて
Even the eternal lady turns her head away
天国は遠く向こうの方へ
And heaven is far off in the distance
ああ　飽かせた　黄昏　惑わせる
Ah, grown tired of it, the twilight bewilders
ただここでもいいから　遠くへ
I just want to go far away, even from here
行きたいんだ　それだけなんだ
I want to go, that's all there is to it
吹き荒れて　研ぎ澄ませ　響き出した音を逃すな
Blow wildly, sharpen your senses,
don't miss the sound that's ringing out
呼吸を整えて
Steady your breathing
助けに来るはずもない
No one is coming to save you
黄金の命題を
The golden proposition
今きっと掴んで離すな
Now, surely, grasp it and don't let go
アイムアルーザー　なんもないなら
I'm a loser, if there's nothing
どうなったっていいだろう
Then what does it matter what happens?
うだうだして　フラフラしていちゃ
If you're just idling and wandering aimlessly
今に　灰さよなら
Before you know it, you'll be ash—goodbye
アイムアルーザー　きっといつかって
I'm a loser, 'surely someday'...
願うまま　進め
As you wish, keep moving forward
ロスタイムのそのまた奥へ
Even further into the loss time
愛されたいならそう言えよ
If you want to be loved, just say so
思ってるだけじゃ伝わんないね
It won't get across if you just think it
永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて
Even the eternal lady turns her head away
天国は遠く向こうの方へ
And heaven is far off in the distance
ここいらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ
Let's dance a bit around here
夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until the break of dawn
聞こえてんなら声出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, let out your voice
アイムアルーザー　どうせだったら
I'm a loser, if that's the case anyway
遠吠えだっていいだろう
A howl would be just fine, wouldn't it?
もう一回　もう一回
One more time, one more time
行こうぜ　僕らの声
Let's go, with our voices
アイムアルーザー　ずっと前から
I'm a loser, from way back
聞こえてた　いつか
I've been hearing it, one day...
ポケットに隠した声が
The voice hidden in my pocket
ここいらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ
Let's dance a bit around here
夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until the break of dawn
聞こえてんなら声出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, let out your voice
てーきあつ まけないもん！
I won't lose to low pressure!
尾丸ポルカ 生誕祭 2023
Omaru Polka Birthday Festival 2023
ありがとう
Thank you
低気圧お疲れ様でした！
Good job everyone for the Teikiatsu live!
ぜひ感想ハッシュタグでお待ちしてます！
I'm looking forward to your thoughts with the hashtag!
みんなも、ゲストのみんなー！
Everyone, and guests, everyone!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ポルカお疲れー！
Good job, Polka!
お疲れー！
Good job!
ポルポーありがとう！
Polpo, thank you!
愛してるぞー！
I love you!
よかったよー！
It was great!
花丸あげちゃう！
I'll give you a gold star!
最高のライブだったよー！
It was the best live ever!
これから面談行ってくるー！ありがとー！
I'm going to a meeting now! Thank you!
お、頑張ってー！
Oh, good luck!
行ってらっしゃーい！
Take care!
ポルポー頑張れー！
Polpo, do your best!
行ってらっしゃーい！
Take care!